In this segment, we're going to talk about how to do gum massage on your dog.
The younger the dog is, the easier it is to get them used to having your fingers into their mouths.
And it's very important to massage their gums, as important as it to brush their teeth.
And by massaging their gums, you're moving the circulation, keeping their gums healthy.
So you can just start on one side and do small circles all the way around their gums.
And they will lick and they may try and get your fingers out of there and you just have to keep at it and get them used to it.
Yes.
Sometimes you can use a little bit of doggy toothpaste in a flavor that they like and that'll help them get used to licking your fingers and liking your fingers in their mouth.
And small circles are the best and all the way around, making sure to get both the top and the bottom.
And you don't have to spend a lot of time doing this.
If you do five seconds today, maybe tomorrow you can get ten seconds.
And every day that you get your fingers into your dog's mouth, they're going to tolerate it a little more.
And, if you start as puppies, they're really going to be used to it and not push you out.